A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 21; APCS (Box Box 3)
    re boating
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 23; ALS, 6 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    mentioning a boat trip around Traverse Bay with Mamie Teasdale Wheless, her delight with Charlevoix and Sara Teasdale and her family, and wanting to discuss plans with him
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 26; ALS, 4 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    discussing a trip around Pine Lake on a "miniature ferry," plans for leaving there and returning to Tucson, Arizona, mentioning Sara Teasdale's and her poetry writing, receiving "Mr. Sappho's" [John Myers O'Hara] new book,
    Songs of the Open
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 28; APCS (Box Box 3)
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Aug 31; APCS (Box Box 3)
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Sep 1; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    re personal matters and plans for leaving
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Sep 2; APCS (Box Box 3)
    writing about Marion Cummings Stanley's visit, on a postcard with a view of a river, "The Old Channel," in Charlevoix
  - Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, 1909 Sep 2; APCS (Box Box 3)
    sending a postcard with another view of a river, "Old River," in Charlevoix
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Charlevoix, Michigan, to Bruce M. Stanley, Los Angeles, California, 1909 Sep 4; ALS, 3 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    writing personal news
  - Alexander N. DeMenil, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Sep 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    ] and praising her work
  - Madison Cawein, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Oct 3; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    praising her book,
    , commenting on "Japanese Incense" as being "as fragrant in words as is the perfume it speaks," and saying that her love-songs are as lovely as those of Sappho
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Oct 15; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    sending pictures of the buildings in which she is spending time, and reminiscing about time spent with Marion Cummings Stanley
  - Clayton Hamilton, Associate Editor, The Forum, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Nov 8; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    accepting her poem, "To Cleis," for publicaton
  - Chen E. Cory, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1909 Dec 13; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the gift
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Dec 21; ANS, w/env. (Box Box 3)
    sending a Christmas greeting
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1909 Dec 28; APCS (Box Box 3)
    thanking him for the candy
  - Alfred Edward Housman, University College, London, England, to Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, 1910 Jan 1; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    sending his appreciation of her gift of the book [
  - Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, to Editor, The Forum, New York, New York, 1910 Jan 10; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    requesting the return of her short monologue, "Sappho," with ANS from the Editor saying that they are using it in the February issue
  - Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Jan 17; APCS (Box Box 3)
    thinking of her in this "loveliest, quaintest town"
  - Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, to Bruce M. Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1910 Feb 10; APCS (Box Box 3)
    thanking him for the gift of "the dear little Japanese girl feeding the fawns"
  - Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Feb 20; APCS (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for "the interesting sixteenth century gentleman with a telephone receiver"
  - Sara Teasdale, The Valencia, St. Augustine, Florida, to Bruce M. Stanley, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, 1910 Mar 17; APCS (Box Box 3)
  - Caroline Risque to Frank George, Hutchinson, Kansas, 1910 Mar 23; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    receiving the baby picutres of Barbara George and the newborn, and asking that the
    be sent to Lillie Rose Ernst at Hosmer Hall
  - Frances M. Weir, Kensington, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Apr 14; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem, "Pierrot," and giving some information about herself including being a student of Leopold Godowsky
  - Olive Ruby Hammon, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Apr 20; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem, "Daisy Time"
  - Jessie Johnston Linton, Chigaco, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1910 Jul 21; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem, "Pierrot"
  - The Century Company, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1910 Aug 23; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    enclosing a letter from someone in Aberdeen, Scotland requesting permission to use one of her poems
  - Joan A. Rae, Aberdeen, Scotland, to Editor, Century Magazine, 1910 Aug; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    wishing to obtain Sara Teasdale's consent for publishing a song with her poem, "Daisy Time," set to music
  - George Sterling, Carmel, California, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1910 Aug 27; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    discussing "Miss French's" work in poetry, gladly accepting Sara Teasdale's praise of his own work, and mentioning John Myers O'Hara and his "Sapphic poems"
  - Joan A. Rae, Aberdeen, Scotland, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1910 Aug 30; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    requesting permission to publish as a song her poem "Daisy Time" which she has set to music
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Sep 8; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    re using her poems
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Sep 20; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    sending a check in payment for two of her poems to be published in
    Putnam's Monthly
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Oct 27; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    concerning her poem, "Erinna," which is to appear in their second issue, and mentioning as among her admirers, Louis Untermeyer, Mitchell Kennerley, Michael Monahan, and Richard Le Galliene
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, The Moods Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Nov 28; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l. (Box Box 3)
    concerning the publication of her volume of poems, their undertaking the publishing of four or five volumes of verse as well as the second book of "The Younger Choir," and companies wanting a guarantee of sales when publishing poetry
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Dec 13; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    offering her a publishing proposition for her volume of verse specifying that she would bear the entire cost of production
  - Williamina Parrish, New York, New York, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Dec 14; APCS (Box Box 3)
  - Robert Underwood Johnson, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1910 Dec 30; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    accepting her poem, "The Wind," for publication
  - Albert Victor Young, Cable Hall, Knoxville, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Jan 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
  - Vine Colby to Petronelle Sombart, 1911 Jan 13; ALS, 5 p. on 5 l. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the lace jabot, describing at great length the Potter party, and mentioning each of the Potters
  - Robert Underwood Johnson, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 6; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    according her the right to make further use of her verse, "Song," published by the magazine last July in her book or in a musical setting, and accepting her poem, "The Wind," for publication
  - Charles Hanson Towne, Editor, The Delineator, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 8; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for her letter and volume,
  - George Sylvester Viereck, Viereck Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    returning the "Young Choir" with his signature
  - Witter Bynner, Hotel Seymour, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 15; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    concerning an evening of poetry [a meeting of the Poetry Society of America]
  - Joseph Benson Gilder, Editor, The Saturday Review of Books, The New York Times, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 26; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    giving his weekday schedule
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, Secretary, The Poetry Society of America, Gramercy Park, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 26; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    wanting to meet her at the next meeting and commenting that Sara Teasdale's "Helen," read by Witter Bynner, was well accepted
  - Henry Mills Alden, Editor, Harper's Magazine, Harper & Brothers, Franklin Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 27; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
  - Ernest R. Kroeger, Director, the Kroeger School of Music, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1911 Feb 28; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    writing that he has set to music two of her poems, "Buried Love" and "Pierrot"
  - John Shea, University of Kansas, Lawrence, Kansas, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Mar 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    finding her quatrain "At Night" to be pure and true
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Mar 30; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    ], and saying it was both a pleasure to read it and to meet her, and commenting that "poets are the most charming people on earth"
  - Albert Victor Young, Piano and Harmony, Knoxville, Tennessee, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Apr 19; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for giving him permission to use her poems, "Daisy Time" and "Song" as musical settings, and asking permission to use "Twilight"
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1911 July 1; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking him for his note about a photograph of herself she had sent
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, The Moods Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 July 6; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
    calling her "On the Tower" a magnificent piece of work and printing it in the August issue
  - Natalie Bigelow, Evanston, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1911 Aug 10; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    requesting permission to submit for publication a musical setting of her poem, "The Prayer"
  - Natalie Bigelow, Evanston, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, Charlevoix, Michigan, 1911 Aug 28; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for her courtesy and for the pleasure her poems give her
  - H. Alexander Matthews, Germantown, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, [Charlevoix, Michigan], 1911 Sep 6; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    acknowledging receipt of her lyrics, and asking her charge for using them
  - R.E. Lee Gibson, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 9; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    giving high praise to her work in the book of poems [
    Helen of Troy and Other Poems
    ], and wanting to write a nice review for
    The Hesperian
  - Madison Cawein, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 10; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    praising her book of poems [
    Helen of Troy...
    ], especially the love songs, and wanting to send her a copy of his selected
    Poems
  - George Sylvester Viereck, The Viereck Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the gift of the charming book [
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, The Moods Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 10; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    commenting on her book of poems,
  - Alexander N. DeMenil, The Hesperian, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 10; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the copy of
    and wishing her success
  - Lily S. Anthony, Montrose, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 11; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the gift, [
    ], and planning to read the verses with her husband on their wedding trip
  - John Myers O'Hara, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 11; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the volume, [
    ], and commenting on its "lyric splendor"
  - Orrick Johns, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 12; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    ], saying that he has written a review of her book for
    The Mirror
    , and commenting that "On the Tower" us "dramatic promise as well as fine poetry"
  - Robert Underwood Johnson, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 13; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    , and sending in return a copy of his
  - Marion Cummings Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 13; ALS, 6 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    calling the verses in her book, [
    ] "dear and familiar," showing pride in the dedication, saying that she was glad the book arrived after her spell of illness and melancholy and that she is looking forward to better health and the success of her own book
  - Witter Bynner, Windsor, Vermont, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the book
    , and promising to copy some verses for her
  - Paul Y. Tupper, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 16; ALS, 2 p.on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    referring to her new book,
    Helen to Troy...
    , as a "perfect delight," and thanking her for the copy
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 17; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    commenting that Orrick Johns has written a fine review of
  - Willa Sibert Cather, Cherry Valley, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 19; ALS, 2 p.on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the volume of
    , and mentioning the lyrics she especially liked
  - Thekla Bernays, The Washington, St. Louis, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 21; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the gift of her book,
    , and commenting that the love-songs are her favorite and that they "have that artlessness that signifies the mastery of art"
  - Henry Mills Alden, Editor, Harper's Magazine, Harper & Brothers, Franklin Square, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 23; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for sending the volume of verse,
    , and indicating that it has already become a family treasure
  - Homer Croy, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 23; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the book,
    , and mentioning his boarders' reaction to the volume
  - Alfred Edward Housman, Trinity College, Cambridge, England, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 25; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    thanking her for the gift of her poems,
  - Mrs. A.D. Kerry, Seattle, Washington, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 27; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 3)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem, "Twilight," with ANS from her mother, Mary Elizabeth Willard Teasdale, on back
  - Louis Untermeyer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 27; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    admiring her "powers & artistic discrimination," commenting on his own verse, "The Poet," which Sara Teasdale had praised, sending her "a little burlesque volume,"
    The Younger Quire
    , saying she will like the review of her
    , and praising her work
  - William H. Gardner, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    expressing his enjoyment of her poems, extending congratulations on her book,
    , commenting on Charles Hanson Towne's splendid work, and saying that his own "sense of rhythm is so lyrical in style..."
  - S.T. Newton, Essex County, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Oct 30; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 3)
    requesting some biographical information for his upcoming article on poets
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 5; ALS, 5 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    , discussing a trip to Europe and plans for a future trip abroad, and mentioning a meeting of the Poetry Society of America with a discussion of the Irish plays and invluding interesting persons such as Henry Van Dyke and Curtis Hidden Page
  - Frederick Oakes Sylvester, Central High School, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 5; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing his appreciation of the gift of her book,
    , and sending a token in return
  - John Myers O'Hara, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 8; ALS, 6 p. on 3 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    giving high praise to her book of verse,
    , calling "Helen of Troy" and "On the Tower" "postive triumphs," critiquing several of the poems, comparing her favorably to Elizabeth Barrett Browning and Christina Rossetti, and writing a French translation of "The Pagan End"
  - John L. Hervey, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 11; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for the volume of her poems,
    , calling her "a real poet," and saying that it will be a delightful privilege to read her new poems
  - F. Dewey Richards, The Friars, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to publish his musical setting of her verse, "Song," and asking to use the first line as the title
  - Julia Marlowe Sothern, Manhattan Opera House, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 24; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    wishing to meet with her to discuss her book,
  - Julia G. Scott, President General, National Society Daughters of the American Revolution, Washington, D.C., to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 20; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    sending thanks for her book of verse,
  - Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 30; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    reminiscing about a Thanksgiving dinner with Marion Cummings Stanley and Sara, writing about Marion's despair over the illness of her mother, and expressing his delight in reading her book,
  - Frank K. Hallack, Cromwell Hall, Cromwell, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Nov 24; ALS,; 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    and commenting on her great talent
  - Edward L. Preetorius, President, The Saint Louis Times, St. Louis, Missouri, to Louis H. Behrens, Times Building, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 1; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    re a column review of Sara Teasdale's book,
    , in the following day's paper
  - Theodosia Garrison, Elizabeth, New Jersey, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 3; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing her pleasure at receiving her book,
    , and encouraging her to "keep on singing-for all of us"
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1911 Dec 4; ALS, 7 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    reminiscing about her stay with him and Marion Cummings Stanley, and asking him to send a copy of her book (which she will supply),
    , to Richard LeGallienne of
    Harper's Magazine
    , under his own name
  - Madison Cawein, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 5; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    drawing her attention to the notice of her book,
    , in the Sunday
    New York Times
  - Paul E. More, The Nation, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 6; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    looking forward to reading her volume of verse,
    , and hoping that their reviewer will mention it
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1911 Dec 10; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    enclosing some clippings for Marion Cummings Stanley, planning to mail her book,
    to him to send to Richard LeGallienne, and mentioning her poor health
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 11; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    commenting on the
    St. Louis Times
    review of her book,
    , and on their literary relationship
  - Charles E. Savage, G. P. Putnam's Sons, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 12; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    apologizing for the delay in sending copies of
    to periodicals she requested, and returning the reviews of her book
  - John Sanburn Phillips, Editor, The American Magazine, 1911 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    accepting "The Lights of New York," "Sea Longing," and "Triolets" for publication
  - B. Russell Herts, Editor, The International, The Moods Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    accepting one of her sonnets for the next issue and revealing that Louis Untermeyer will be reviewing her book,
    , in the current issue
  - Edith M. Thomas, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 15; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    praising the verses in her book,
    and commenting on their beauty
  - Thomas C. Clark, Albiou, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 15; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    reminding her of her promise to present a copy of her book,
    , to him
  - Elizabeth K. Mew, Indianapolis, Indiana, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 16; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    sending holiday greetings and commenting "how pleasing to turn to a comforting poem and find solace in a kindred spirit"